Thank you for watching!
Hello everyone!
I am Liloa Aoi and Miyu Yanagi.
Nice to meet you.
Today, Fukuoka Prefecture...
Sorry.
Today we are here at Tokai University Fukuoka High School in Munakata City, Fukuoka Prefecture.
Yay!
Today is the second location for a filming where we are making picture plates out of recycled PET bottle paper,
We did the last location shoot at Liremieux, too,
It was fun.
It was a lot of fun.
We got to go around the factory and made some amazing picture plates.
You know...you know.
We wrote on paper, you know.
It was a lot of fun.
Yes, it was.
Last time, I just wrote a draft from a sheet of paper,
I would like to narrow down the contents more,
I would like to get ideas from many people to make it better than just us,
So today, we would like to have the students of this high school cooperate with us.
So, here they are!
Yay!
By the way, this high school was last year,
They also provided the boost for the Nakata festival last year,
That plastic bottle...
Yeah, yeah. Yes, yes...
You know, the caps... Hey, let's put that cap on like...
Yes!
We did the cap art together...
I've done a lot of cap art with you, you know,
I'm glad to be able to do it again.
I'm looking forward to it!
Yes, today we have a special picture book making...
Yes?
Yes!
Today, not only the students, but also a special guest who is perfect for making picture books,
We also have a special guest who is perfect for making picture books!
He will appear later, so please look forward to his appearance!
Okay, let's go to the classroom!
Let's go!
When out of sight!
I'm here!
I'm here! Oh, my God!
What is it?
Where is it? Over there.
The inn.
All right, let's go in.
Come on in.
One at a time.
One toilet. One time in the bathroom.
Excuse me.
Hello.
I'm Liloa Aoi and Mie Yanagi from Mattenshoe itself.
Pleased to meet you.
Today, we'd like to ask you to help us make a picture book.
We're here to help you make a picture book.
Thank you very much.
Please introduce yourself.
I'm Mayu.
I'm Akari.
I'm Sae
I'm Mae.
Nice to meet you.
Why?
I'm your sister.
And you.
Please...
Please, please, please.
Today we have a very special guest.
I have a special guest who is indispensable to the making of this picture book.
who is indispensable to the making of this picture book.
Let me introduce you to her.
Risa Karalizm, art performer.
Risa, I'm looking forward to working with you.
I'm looking forward to working with you.
Thank you very much.
Thank you very much.Thank you.
I am an art performer.
My name is Risa Karalizm.
I'm an art performer, and I'm from and live in Tokyo.
And I graduated from Tokai High School.
That's great.
I miss it so much.
I'm glad to be here.
It's nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you.
This is my senior.
I'm a senior.
We've never met you before.
What kind of activities do you usually do?
Well...
I'm an art performer.
I think most of my work is done on a desk.
I do large paintings on stage and finish them in a short time.
on stage in a very short time.
It's amazing!
I don't just paint the finished work.
The picture changes in the middle of the painting.
It's like a picture-story show.
Each scene has its own meaning
It's a performance with a story.
That's amazing.
It's so old, it's embarrassing.
So long ago, so embarrassing
Amazing. Great.
It takes me about 10 minutes.
I drew it in about 10 minutes.
That's amazing.
Amazing.
Amazing!
So I hope I can help to make this picture book
I hope I can cooperate with you in the creation of this picture book.
Thank you very much.
I'd like to ask Lisa to help me with the illustrations
I'd like you to help me with the illustrations.
I'd like you to help us...
We've been working on the story for a while.
We've been thinking about it for a while.
Can I share it with you?
Yes, we'd love to hear it.
That's difficult.
Ready, go!
Is this the Mr. Plastic Bottle I've heard so much about?
Oh, yes.
I like rumors of rumors.
Come on, Mr. Plastic Bottle.
Read it in English and wait a minute.
Happy.
Yes, first of all, there's Mr. Pet Bottle.
This is Mr. Pet Bottle, the boy on the right.
Mr. PET Bottle is full of drinks right now, but he's running out of them.
But he's running out of drink, and this little guy is drinking from him. They ran out, and this girl's people swallowed them up.
When it was gone, they threw it away. They threw it into the sea.
I was so sad, I didn't want to throw it away, when Lil' Mew found it.
And then Lil' Mew found it and said, "What's with the plastic bottle?
She washed him clean and recycled his hair.
And then he was recycled and became hair.
It's a story with a happy ending.
Amazing!
So cute!
Watch it.
It's cute.
I did it! She said it was cute even though she didn't show up.
I'm glad.
I'm almost the same as Lila.
Yes...
First of all, this is a PET bottle of green tea.
At first, the bottles are filled to the brim, and people are happy.
But when they finish drinking, they are thrown away into the sea.
But when the bottles are finished, they are thrown away into the sea.
And then this Lil' Mu appears.
And then, this Lil' Mew appears and says, "Lil' Mew, it's me!
And then, this PET bottle is regenerated and becomes a new PET bottle.
And then this PET bottle is reborn as a new PET bottle...
And then we meet Lil' Mu again... happy ending!
So cute!
I'm so happy!
Which story will you go with?
Cars?
What? What's the difference?
It's the last one. It's the last one.
The last one?
Yeah, the last one.
This one goes on paper.
Then two.
And then a plastic bottle.
back to a plastic bottle?
Yes, sir.
I made the paper from plastic bottles, and then I made the picture book.
I think we talked about how paper is better.
I think we talked about that.
That's right.
Paper.
Maybe you're right.
Familiarity.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
It would be nice if the customers could hold this picture book in their hands and feel that it's made from plastic bottles.
It would be nice if the customers could feel that the picture book they hold in their hands is made of plastic bottles.
Yes, that's right.
That's right.
The point is to see what the reader finds most interesting.
I see.
I think so.
I think that if we delve deeper into this part with the sensibility of a high school student...
I wonder if there is something that could be interesting to young people of all ages.
How to help
I see...
Lil' Mu is here, and he's like, "Wow! Lil' Mew came in and was like, "Wow!
So I was wondering if you could elaborate on that.
How to help.
A cute way to help.
I'm counting on you.
Go!
Oh, a plastic bottle.
A plastic bottle.
Oh, poor baby.
Let's help him.
Lil' Mew, come here.
You're an angel.
Oh, an angel.
We're going to die.
I'm going to die.
I'll be back.
I'll come back.
I'll be reborn.
My little angel...
Tonight she's wearing the director's clothes. Next, I like her face.
Yes, ma'am.
Come home, all of you.
Come back, all of you.
Come back all together.
Come back all together
All of you come back
Eh, I'm...
I want the bubbles...
I want to take...I want to take
Real PET Bottle
Oh, sorry.
Then I guess I'd prefer green tea for the PET bottle.
Eh, but also your favorite juice.
Even like this.
Eh, what am I writing?
Okay, just this once.
You know how I decided?
Okay, just this one time.
I don't know if you know what I'm talking about.
I think it would be better if you set up the people and the background of the bottles in a way that's easy for people who are new to it to understand.
I think it would be good to set up the people in a way that is easy for newcomers to understand.
And the location.
I think you should write more details.
Thank you very much.
I think I chose the ocean as the place where they meet.
That's why I started with people.
You start with people.
Nasirimyu and PET bottle Nasirimyu
I see.
But they're cute when they're human, right?
It's really cute.
It's big and thick too.
I prefer this carbon one.
And...
Ew.
I like the milk.
I said the same thing.
I said the same thing. I said the same thing.
What is there to drink in Fukuoka?
Maybe we could make something?
Fukuoka
Speaking of which...
Mentaiko (cod roe) juice
Ha-ha-ha-ha!
It's good, it's good, it's good.
Really
Mentaiko
Juice.
I forgot all about Mr. Kohli's juice.
Mentaiko juice.
It's disgusting. All the grains are disgusting.
I haven't felt that way in a long time.
I think it's interesting how young people...
I think it's interesting how young people can be so open-minded.
And the spells?
The spells are just too ingenious.
I'm a bit of a liller.
I see.
I don't know.
I only had to come up with one.
You have 30 seconds.
What?
Open the light, too.
Let's see what's up.
Oh!
Hey.
Everyone's in perfect condition.Yeah, they're all in tune.
Oh, my God.
It's so nice to get rid of Breathtis.
And get some other people to take pictures of you, too.
That's what I'm talking about.
This is the fantasy one.
This is the big fantasy one.
50 years old.
It's so chaotic.
This is it.
Here we go.
This is great! You've got a great idea!
Okay, may I start with Sae-chan's presentation?
First of all, when Mirumiyu-chan and I went to the beach together, she found an empty plastic bottle on the beach, and she decided to stop using it.
Then she sees it, but when she tries to pass by it, the plastic bottle starts talking.
Then we both washed the bottle and recycled it,
A year later, when they were in a bookstore together, they met the recycled plastic bottle again, bought the book, and cherished it for a long time.
I bought the book and cherished it forever.
Amazing!
A great story about a bookstore!
Wow!
You've done it already!
It's done!
That's great!
No, no, no, there's more.
Look at it!
I was playing in the ocean with my child first.
I was thirsty, so I said I would buy a bottle of water from a vending machine at the beach.I was thirsty, so I said I would buy a bottle of water from a vending machine at the beach, and bought a plastic bottle of water.
When I finished drinking it, I littered it all over the beach,
And when he finished drinking it, he littered it on the beach,
When I finished my drink, I littered the beach,
Lil' Mew and his friends who were playing there found it.
They decided to pick it up because it was dangerous, so they went to recycle it, and it turned from plastic bottles to paper, and then they met again.
Amazing!
Cute!
Stellar Pokoro,
I love that Stellar Pokoro is written right on it.
Yeah, yeah.
You're gonna do it, aren't you?
And you're doing it as an innocent child.
I'm sure.
I'd like to, you know, stop filling my own plastic bottles,
But when I need help, it's at the Breast-shaped Festival. But I wanted to have Lil' Mu save me at the beach, since the sternum festival is also near the ocean,
I wanted to ask Lil' Mu to save me,
I wanted to have Lil' Mu help me,
I wanted L'il Mu to help me,
I wanted to have Lil' Mu help me, and I wanted to have Lil' Mu help me,
I couldn't think of a person who would be made, you know, to be littered by a certain person,
I wanted to make it so that people would not litter, so I thought it would be nice if we could meet again as paper.
That's all.
I really like the specific part about the stiffness of the heart, and the part about not littering anymore, about changing the mind.
Thank you very much.
That's wonderful.
I'm glad.
Yes, I'm off.
Well, Lila also thought the ocean would be nice, so I decided to go to the ocean in Munakata, Well, Lilla also thought that the ocean would be nice, so we decided to use the sea in Munakata,
I thought it would be nice if the four of us could come out to the sea as well, since we all thought of it together,
I thought it would be nice if the four of them came out to play together, and then, when they finished drinking out of the plastic bottles, they would throw them away,
I wrote something about this hat because I thought the bottle might be a boy's hat,
I thought it would be cute if the hat were to disappear when the bottle was thrown away,
I thought it would be cute if the hat was thrown away and the drink was lost, so I recreated it as it is in this drawing,
I thought it would be cute if the hat was thrown away and lost, so I recreated it as it is in the picture, and Mayuka-chan had strawberry milk, and I thought it would be nice since Lira likes strawberries,
I thought it would be good because Mayuka likes strawberry milk, and I thought it would be good because Lira likes strawberries, so I took a little bit of the picture book,
I thought, "Well, this picture book is something that can be passed down from little children to adults,
The hair was recycled, and the plastic bottles were turned into paper,
I hope it will inspire people to recycle,
I want to make it into a picture book!
What, a hat?
I want to make a picture book about a plastic bottle in Lilah, who wears a hat, and that hat becomes a cap, and then the hat disappears,
If the hat is lost when you drink..,
Oh, that's another thing,
You know,
A henyo henyo feeling?
A henyo henyo feeling!
I made it and put it on.
No, I thought it looked interesting,
I thought I'd adopt it.
Thank you very much.
Okay, okay.
I see.
Thank you very much.
I see,
Let's go into the fantasy zone,
Let's go into the fantasy zone.
Enter the fantasy zone.Into the fantasy zone.
I want my drink to be pretty,
Strawberry milk.
Are you okay?
And I was like, well, I don't care where you are.
I thought everyone knew best.
I got a pick-me-up.
And I was like the devil and the angel as the main characters.
The demon kind of fell in love.
And then the angel sees that and thinks, "Oh, no, I can't do that.
So he saves the bottle with his magic.
And to tell this story...
The plastic bottle became a piece of paper
It's like a picture book, and it's going to be published all over the world.
Oh! Worldwide!
All over the world!
That's great!
Let's take it to the world.
Demons and angels.
Demons and Angels
You can use it from this beach
To the world.
I think we can use it.
I have a drawing.
Yes, you do.
You know, super sparkly.
Oh, this is the devil doing it.
He's looking at the angel and saying, "I laid down summer...
Cute.
Sparkles. sparkle
Mzuzu.
What's a plastic bottle?
PET bottles are made of strawberry milk.
I drew strawberries.
I see.
That's cute.
Thank you.
It's important.
Well, we came up with the idea together, so it's almost the same.
I was advised to use Fukuoka ingredients for the juice, so I made cod roe juice.
So we decided to use cod roe juice.
I heard there is a sea called Genkai.
I heard there is a sea called Genkai, so I decided to use Genkai.
So I decided to use Genkai.
So, I wrote a story about a witch and a fairy.
They litter, and they do it in the city and so on.
Then the bottles are damaged and end up in the ocean.
That's why they are suffering at that time.
So I thought I could convey the message that littering should not be done.
I see.
And I thought that Rira and Miu have a good name, Lil Miu.
I made them fairies, and I thought fairies use magic.
I thought that fairies use magic, so I asked Lil' Miu to help me with magic.
And now that I have magic, I will use magic to become a god.
I'm thinking that I can use recycled words for the spells.I'm thinking of using words for spells and other words that are recycled.
And the picture book made from this paper will be a treasure for the two Lil' Miu's. That's the end of it!
Wow, that's great!
Appealing!
I love the idea of depicting this scene of hurt and suffering.
It actually makes me want to help them.
It's so nice!
I was wondering what would happen when the cod roe juice came out.
Surprisingly, you did it right.
Cute.
You got it right.
Thank you.
I'm curious what the magic spell will be.
Let's decide on that.
Recycle.
Okay.
I don't know.
I wanted to use the word "recycle" in a cute way.
Isn't that kind of high school girlish?
I like it.
I don't know.
Isn't there a word that's popular right now?
God.
God?
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
It's like, "Be God.
You know, that sentence.
That sentence. Sentence.
I don't...
I don't want to eat recycled food.
Hey, aren't I kind of the specialty of the two of us?
Not your area of expertise?
Il-ah?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Ilua's got a lot of stuff.
Oh, my God, you're scaring me.
Yeah, I know.
Uh, throw the card.
Recycle, what do you mean, "regenerate"?
Recycle?
Is there another way to say it?
Recycle.
Reuse Reduce
Recycle
What's in it for you?
Any changes?
Oh.
What?
Changey.
No, that's something.
Wait a minute.
Change, it's too wide. It makes sense.
Yeah, it does.
Too wide?Too much?
Recycle.
You just made a change. What?
Recycle
Recycle?
Re-change? It's possible.
Recycle, change, rechange.
I was thinking...
What's that?
I was thinking that you should use the word "recycle.
I see.
Keep it.
I want the word "recycle" to be cute.
Weirdly.
I thought it would be cute in katakana.
It's only "katakana".
Recycle,
For example, ć
kuru kuru
Recycle
means?
recycle
Recycle.
We're gonna use it.Use the jean.
If it fits your high school girl's sense of style.
Recycle Cru Change
Recycle
change
Recycle-Curu-Change
Do you write "change"?
No, I've never seen it.
C of change
Kuru-kuru-change.
Which way is "C"?
This way.
"C" for change.
It's the other way around.
It's the other way.
To the other guy!
Come on!
Kururu-change.
What do you mean?
Did you stop it?
Change of turn
C
Camera-wise.
Is that what you're doing?
Reverse the usual zoom.
C
Like this, guys.This is what I'm talking about.
You sure you want to change?
This way, then.
This way or this way?
This way.
All right, let's do it this way or that way.
Ready?
Recycle-Change
Recycle change
Recycle 'em, recycle 'em, recycle 'em, recycle 'em.
That's great.
Great.
Cute.
So much in such a short time.
That's wonderful.
Let's put this in a picture book.
Page spread.
One page.
I've come up with something like this, but would you be willing to work with me on it again?
Yes, by all means.
Thank you very much.
Thank you very much for your nice feedback.
Thank you for the same opinion.
Thank you very much.
I'd like to do something with the guests who come to the Murakata Festival on the day of the event.
Can I ask for your help with that too?
Of course!
I have a 3-meter campus.
Three meters? 3m?
And by the way, we have a 5m one.
We have a really big campus.
I'd like to paint on that big campus with everyone, including those who come on the day of the event.
I hope we can paint together.
That would be great!
I want to draw pictures with everyone.
I'd like to use it in connection with a picture book.
Wow!
Let's make a picture book together!
Please do!
Thank you very much for your time today.
I know you've been thinking of ideas for picture books and stuff, but how was it?
I'm glad we thought about things we don't usually think about, and it was fun to think about it together.
I'm glad.
I'm glad we had this opportunity to think together about things we don't usually do.
It was fun because we could come up with all kinds of ideas like this.
I'm looking forward to seeing the finished product that we all came up with.
How was it?
Yes, I did.
There were more opinions than I expected.
I thought it was amazing.
I couldn't have imagined such a variety of opinions.
I hope I can make it into a proper form
I hope to be able to deliver it as a picture book.
I will not waste the thoughts of my juniors.
Finally, from November 3rd to 5th
The 3-day chest-shaped festival will be held from November 3 to 5!
We'll be broadcasting live from the site on our Google channel.
on November 4th and 5th.We will be holding this event on November 4 and 5.
We are looking forward to seeing you there!
On November 4th and 5th
We are planning to hold an event where everyone can paint on this large canvas
We are planning to have some events where everyone can paint on this large canvas.
Please come to the festival!
On our Google channel
on our Google channel! We will also open the lawn to the public for free on the day of the festival.
And on the day of the festival, the lawn will be open to the public for free.
So please come and join us!
Bye bye!